<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="Basic NCD Data Reduction">
   <intro>
      <description>
         Prerequisites:<br/><br/>
         Create project with data<br/>
         Load detector information
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
         title="Selecting sector region">
      <description>
         If data reduction process includes sector integration stage, please open one of the images and select &quot;Radial Profile&quot; and/or &quot;Azimuthal Profile&quot;tool
         to check corresponding integrated profiles. Adjust sector dimensions, if needed. <br/>
         <b>Important!</b> Please take care not to move the sector region while trying to adjust dimensions. If sector region is accidentally moved, it can be returned back to the currently set
         beam center position pressing &quot;Center sector&quot; button on the integrated profile plot toolbar. When appropriate sector region size is selected,
         it is recommended to select &quot;Lock to Metadata&quot; button that positions sector origin at currently set beam stop position and fixes region so that it can't be accidentally moved. <br/>
         Current beam center position can be checked in the table view in &quot;Diffraction&quot; tool. It gets updated when NCD calibration procedure is completed or q-axis calibration data is loaded from NCD processing results file.
         Pressing lock button on the &quot;Diffraction&quot; tool view toolbar ensures that the currently set metadata will not be accidentally overwritten by opening a file with a header containing different metadata.               
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Specify experiment type">
      <description>
         Select SAXS and/or WAXS checkboxes in &quot;NCD Detector parameters&quot; view to process SAXS and/or WAXS data, respectively.
         For each detector select dimension (1D/2D) and specify pixel size (if not preloaded).  
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Specifying data processing results directory">
      <description>
         Specify directory where data processing results will be stored in the &quot;Directory&quot; field in the &quot;NCD Data Reduction Parameters&quot; view. This directory can be selected by pressing adjacent &quot;...&quot; button and selecting the directory from the dialog. 
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Select pipeline stages">
      <description>
         Pipeline stages are selected in &quot;Data Reduction Pipeline&quot; panel. Indexes indicate order of pipeline execution. 
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Specifying Detector Response parameters">
      <description>
         If &quot;1. Detector Response&quot; stage is enabled we need to specify detector response parameters under &quot;Reference Data&quot; group. 
      </description>
      <subitem>
      	<description>
         Reference to the file with detector response data needs to be specified in &quot;Detector Response File&quot; field. This can be accomplished either by selecting the appropriate file in Project Explorer and selecting NCD &gt; Set as Detector Response File in popup menu or pressing &quot;...&quot; button next to the input field and selecting the file in file dialog. Detector response file should contain only single frame.
      	</description>
      </subitem>   
   </item>
   <item
         title="Specifying Sector Integration parameters">
      <description>
         If &quot;2. Sector Integration&quot; stage is enabled we need to specify parameters under the &quot;Sector Integration Parameters&quot; group. 
      </description>
      <subitem>
      	<description>
         To enable calculation of radial and azimuthal profiles select corresponding checkboxes.
      	</description>
      </subitem>   
      <subitem>
      	<description>
         &quot;Fast Integration&quot; checkbox activates faster but less accurate algorithm for sector integration.
      	</description>
      </subitem>   
      <subitem>
      	<description>
         &quot;Apply Detector Mask&quot; checkbox uses detector mask in integrated profile calculations.<br/>      
         <b>Important!</b> Make sure that mask in visible on the image plot. See &quot;Configuring NCD Data Reduction &gt; Setting Detector Mask&quot; section for further information on loading and saving mask data.
      	</description>
      </subitem>   
      <subitem>
      	<description>
         Selecting checkboxes in &quot;1D SAXS Analysis Data&quot; section will include data for the selected SAXS plots into results files.
         These plots are also accessible via &quot;SAXS Analysis&quot; tool in plot views with integrated data reduction results data.   
      	</description>
      </subitem>   
   </item>
   <item
         title="Specifying Normalisation parameters">
      <description>
         If &quot;3. Normalisation&quot; stage is enabled we need to specify normalisation parameters under &quot;Normalisation&quot; group. 
      </description>
      <subitem>
      <description>
         Select detector name holding normalisation values from &quot;Normalisation Dataset&quot; drop-down list in the &quot;NCD Detector Parameters&quot; view.<br/>
         <b>Important!</b> If the list is empty, repeat &quot;Loading Detector Information&quot; step from &quot;Setup for NCD Data Reduction&quot; section.
      </description>
      </subitem>   
      <subitem>
      <description>
         If normalisation dataset contains values from several channels, specify channel number that should be used for data reduction with &quot;Channel&quot; spinner.
      </description>
      </subitem>   
      <subitem>
      <description>
         Specify scaling value for normalisation data in &quot;Abs. Scale&quot; field (optional).
         This value can be set to calibrate scattering intensity on an absolute scale (see &quot;Absolute Intensity Calibration&quot; section for details).
      </description>
      </subitem>   
   </item>
   <item
         title="Specifying Background Subtraction parameters">
      <description>
         If &quot;4. Background Subtraction&quot; stage is enabled we need to specify background subtraction parameters in &quot;Reference Data&quot; group. 
      </description>
      <subitem>
      <description>
         Reference to the file with background data needs to be specified in &quot;Background Subtraction File&quot; field.
         This can be accomplished either by selecting the appropriate file in Project Explorer and selecting NCD &gt; Set as Background Subtraction File in popup menu or pressing &quot;...&quot; button next to the input field and selecting the file in file dialog.
      </description>
      </subitem>   
      <subitem>
      <description>
         Background data can be rescaled using values specified in &quot;Bg. Scale&quot; field (optional).
      </description>
      </subitem>   
   </item>
   <item
         title="Slicing input data (optional)">
      <description>
         If only part of the input or background data needs to be used the corresponding frame interval can be specified in &quot;Data frame selection&quot; and &quot;Background frame selection&quot; groups. If &quot;First&quot; frame is omitted, data will be selected from the first frame in the dataset. If &quot;Last&quot; frame is omitted, data will be selected until the last frame in the dataset. 
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Running data reduction">
      <description>
         Select single file or multiple files (by holding SHIFT or CTRL) for data reduction in &quot;Project Explorer&quot; view, right-click on them and select &quot;NCD  &gt; Run Data Reduction&quot; menu option. 
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Data reduction results">
      <description>
         Data reduction results are stored in output directory in results_detectorname_DDMMYY_HHMMSS_inputfilename.nxs file under &quot;/entry1/detectorname_processing/&quot; node. Every data reduction stage has separate subnode with output result stored under data subnode.
         Output dataset of NCD data reduction is stored in &quot;/entry1/dtectorname_result/data&quot; node.
      </description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
