<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="Loading Detector Information">
   <intro>
      <description>
         This tutorial explains how to read detector data from data files
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
      title="Selecting data files">
      <description>
         Select single file or multiple NeXus files with your experimental data by holding SHIFT or CTRL keys in the project explorer view. Detectors present only in all the selected files will be loaded into the relevant fields in NCD Detector Parameters and NCD Data Reduction Parameters views.<br/>
         IMPORTANT! For most cases selecting single experimental data file should be enough for setting up detector information. Including files that don't have appropriate structure (e.g. .h5 or processing results files) could prevent correct setting of detector information.<br/>         
         WARNING! Calibration detector is only relevant for Normalisation stage in NCD data reduction. Hence, it can be set only in NCD Data Reduction perspective. If you read detector information in NCD Calibration perspective, Calibration detector will not be set.
         You would need to reload Detector Information in NCD Data Reduction if you want to use Normalisation stage. 
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Read detector information">
      <description>
         Data reduction process utilises three types of detectors: Calibration, WAXS and SAXS.
      </description>
      <subitem
         label="Right-click on the selected files to open pop-up menu.">
      </subitem>   
      <subitem
         label="Select NCD &gt; Read Detector Information option from the pop-up menu.">
      </subitem>   
      <subitem
         label="Inspect detector names added into WAXS and SAXS combo boxes in &quot;NCD Detector Parameters&quot; view and into Normalisation Data combo box under &quot;Reference data&quot; field in &quot;NCD Data Reduction Parameters&quot; view.">
      </subitem>   
   </item>
</cheatsheet>