<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="Setting Detector Mask">
   <intro>
      <description>
         Some detectors have inactive areas or damaged pixels. Masking tool allows us to mark these regions to ignore them in sector integration calculations. This section provides brief description of the Masking tool. For more extensive guide, please refer to the &quot;Masking&quot; cheat sheet in the &quot;Plotting tools&quot; section.
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
         title="Open Masking Tool page">
      <description>
         Select &quot;Masking Tool&quot; option from &quot;Image Tools&quot; button from the toolbar in &quot;Dataset plot&quot; view.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Setting masked intensity thresholds">
      <description>
         &quot;Enable lower mask&quot; and &quot;Enable upper mask&quot; checkboxes activate thresholds for masking pixels with the intensities above or below the levels set in the adjacent spinner controls, respectively.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Using mask drawing tools">
      <description>
         &quot;Enable masking using regions&quot; checkbox adding masked regions using free hand drawing tool and other regions accessible from the toolbar underneath. 
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Applying detector mask in data reduction">
      <description>
         Masking thresholds and regions can be applied clicking &quot;Apply&quot; button or removed with &quot;Reset&quot; button.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Important!!!">
      <description>
         Active mask is erased if plot window switches from 2D image to a different (e.g. 1D) plot mode. To save mask in the internal buffer make sure that &quot;autosave mask to the buffer if it changes&quot; button in the masking tool toolbar is selected.
         This saves mask into internal buffer allowing to load it with &quot;Merge with previously saved mask from buffer...&quot; button if mask gets erased. <b>Mask needs to be visible on the plot before running data reduction</b>.   
      </description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>